export const quizzes = [
	{
		sectionKey: "vodka",
		questions: [
			{
				question: "Which ingredient is commonly used to produce Vodka?",
				answers: ["Barley", "Potatoes", "Rice", "Corn"],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question:
					"What is the primary process involved in the production of Vodka?",
				answers: [
					"Aging in wooden barrels",
					"Distillation and filtration",
					"Fermentation only",
					"Blending with botanicals",
				],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "Which country is historically known for Vodka production?",
				answers: ["United States", "France", "Russia", "Japan"],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "What characteristic is Vodka best known for?",
				answers: [
					"Its color",
					"Its high sugar content",
					"Its neutrality and purity",
					"Its aging process",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "How is Vodka traditionally consumed in Eastern Europe?",
				answers: [
					"Mixed with water",
					"Neat, at room temperature",
					"On the rocks",
					"Chilled, without any additives",
				],
				correctAnswer: 3,
			},
		],
	},
	{
		sectionKey: "gin",
		questions: [
			{
				question: "What is the primary botanical ingredient in Gin?",
				answers: ["Mint", "Rosemary", "Juniper Berries", "Lavender"],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "Which country is credited with the origin of Gin?",
				answers: ["Netherlands", "United Kingdom", "United States", "Italy"],
				correctAnswer: 0,
			},
			{
				question:
					"What is the name of the traditional Gin distillation method?",
				answers: [
					"Pot Still Distillation",
					"Column Still Distillation",
					"Steam Distillation",
					"Vacuum Distillation",
				],
				correctAnswer: 0,
			},
			{
				question:
					"Which of the following cocktails is primarily made with Gin?",
				answers: ["Mojito", "Martini", "Margarita", "Mai Tai"],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "What distinguishes London Dry Gin from other types of Gin?",
				answers: [
					"It must be flavored with artificial additives.",
					"It must be made in London.",
					"It cannot contain any added sugar or color.",
					"It is aged in barrels for a minimum of one year.",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "What is a common method for serving Gin in a Gin & Tonic?",
				answers: [
					"Warm, with a slice of lemon",
					"Neat, with no garnish",
					"Over ice, with a slice of lime",
					"Chilled, straight up",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
		],
	},
	{
		sectionKey: "whiskey",
		questions: [
			{
				question: "What is the main ingredient in whiskey?",
				answers: ["Grapes", "Barley", "Corn", "Potatoes"],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "Which country is known as the birthplace of whiskey?",
				answers: ["Scotland", "United States", "Ireland", "Japan"],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "What does the term 'single malt' refer to?",
				answers: [
					"A whiskey made from a single type of grain",
					"A whiskey made at a single distillery from malted barley",
					"A blend of malted whiskies from different distilleries",
					"A whiskey aged in a single barrel",
				],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "What is the process of aging whiskey called?",
				answers: ["Fermenting", "Distilling", "Maturing", "Blending"],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question:
					"Which of the following is a characteristic flavor of bourbon?",
				answers: ["Peat", "Smoke", "Vanilla", "Seaweed"],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
		],
	},
	{
		sectionKey: "brandy",
		questions: [
			{
				question: "What is brandy distilled from?",
				answers: ["Fruit juice", "Cereal grains", "Sugarcane", "Milk"],
				correctAnswer: 0,
			},
			{
				question: "Which region is famous for producing Cognac?",
				answers: ["Bordeaux", "Champagne", "Normandy", "Cognac"],
				correctAnswer: 3,
			},
			{
				question: "What type of barrels are used to age brandy?",
				answers: ["Steel", "Oak", "Plastic", "Ceramic"],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "How is Armagnac different from Cognac?",
				answers: [
					"It is distilled twice",
					"It is aged longer",
					"It is distilled once",
					"It uses a different type of grape",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "What is the primary flavor profile of brandy?",
				answers: ["Bitter", "Sweet", "Sour", "Umami"],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
		],
	},
	{
		sectionKey: "rum",
		questions: [
			{
				question: "What is rum primarily made from?",
				answers: ["Malted barley", "Grapes", "Sugarcane or molasses", "Corn"],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "Which country is renowned for its rum production?",
				answers: ["Mexico", "Barbados", "Russia", "Canada"],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "What distinguishes 'dark' rum from 'light' rum?",
				answers: [
					"The type of yeast used in fermentation",
					"The length of time it is aged",
					"The color of the bottle",
					"The type of sugarcane used",
				],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "What flavor notes are typical in rum?",
				answers: [
					"Fruity and floral",
					"Smoky and peaty",
					"Sweet and spicy",
					"Bitter and tart",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "What is 'overproof' rum?",
				answers: [
					"Rum with added flavors",
					"Rum that is aged over 50 years",
					"Rum with a higher alcohol content than standard",
					"Rum produced without government oversight",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
		],
	},
	{
		sectionKey: "agave",
		questions: [
			{
				question: "Which plant is used to produce tequila and mezcal?",
				answers: ["Corn", "Blue agave", "Potato", "Sugarcane"],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "What is the key difference between tequila and mezcal?",
				answers: [
					"The region where they are produced",
					"The type of agave used",
					"The distillation process",
					"All of the above",
				],
				correctAnswer: 3,
			},
			{
				question: "Which of the following is NOT an agave-based spirit?",
				answers: ["Sotol", "Bacanora", "Raicilla", "Grappa"],
				correctAnswer: 3,
			},
			{
				question: "How is mezcal traditionally served?",
				answers: [
					"With a worm in the bottle",
					"Chilled with ice",
					"Neat with a side of orange and salt",
					"In a mixed cocktail",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "What does 'añejo' mean in the context of tequila?",
				answers: ["Unaged", "Double distilled", "Aged", "Filtered"],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
		],
	},
	{
		sectionKey: "liqueurs",
		questions: [
			{
				question: "What is a liqueur?",
				answers: [
					"A distilled spirit flavored with herbs, fruits, nuts, or spices",
					"A type of beer",
					"Unflavored distilled spirit",
					"A non-alcoholic beverage",
				],
				correctAnswer: 0,
			},
			{
				question: "Which ingredient is NOT commonly used to flavor liqueurs?",
				answers: ["Cream", "Bark", "Tonic water", "Flowers"],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "What characteristic do all liqueurs share?",
				answers: [
					"High alcohol content",
					"Dark color",
					"Sweetness",
					"Carbonation",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "Which of the following is a famous herbal liqueur?",
				answers: ["Baileys Irish Cream", "Chartreuse", "Cointreau", "Kahlúa"],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "How are cream liqueurs typically consumed?",
				answers: [
					"Mixed with coffee",
					"On the rocks",
					"In shots",
					"All of the above",
				],
				correctAnswer: 3,
			},
		],
	},
	{
		sectionKey: "vermouth",
		questions: [
			{
				question: "What is Vermouth?",
				answers: [
					"A type of beer",
					"An aromatized, fortified wine",
					"A distilled spirit",
					"A non-alcoholic mixer",
				],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "What flavor profile is Amari known for?",
				answers: ["Sweet", "Bitter", "Salty", "Sour"],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "Which botanical is commonly found in bitters?",
				answers: ["Mint", "Gentian root", "Rose petals", "Cucumber"],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "What is the primary use of bitters in cocktails?",
				answers: [
					"To add color",
					"To increase alcohol content",
					"To enhance flavor",
					"To reduce sweetness",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "Which of the following is NOT a type of Vermouth?",
				answers: ["Rosso", "Dry", "Bianco", "Mezcal"],
				correctAnswer: 3,
			},
		],
	},
	{
		sectionKey: "cocktology",
		questions: [
			{
				question: "What is a signature of modern-day bartending?",
				answers: [
					"Use of pre-made mixes",
					"Focus on classic cocktails only",
					"Innovation and use of craft ingredients",
					"Serving drinks without garnishes",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "Which tool is essential for a modern bartender?",
				answers: ["Soda siphon", "Jigger", "Microwave", "Oven"],
				correctAnswer: 1,
			},
			{
				question: "What trend is currently popular in the bartending world?",
				answers: [
					"Artificially flavored spirits",
					"Sugary, high-calorie cocktails",
					"Sustainability and zero waste",
					"Plastic straws and utensils",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question: "How has social media impacted modern bartending?",
				answers: [
					"Decreased interest in cocktail culture",
					"Increased focus on appearance over taste",
					"Enabled the sharing of recipes and techniques globally",
					"Limited the creativity of bartenders",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
			{
				question:
					"What skill is increasingly important for contemporary bartenders?",
				answers: [
					"Ability to work in complete darkness",
					"Knowledge of wine pairings only",
					"Mastery of a wide range of cocktails and spirits",
					"Speed over quality",
				],
				correctAnswer: 2,
			},
		],
	},
];
